# **Curriculum Vitae**





# **JAYAKRISHNAN T V**

jayakrishnantv08@gmail.com Dubai, UAE. +971559312416



#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Desktop Support / Server / Network Engineer Having 4 years of professional experience and skills in a well-established organization. To contribute to the growth of the organization by applying my skills and improving upon it, thus effecting a comprehensive development of my personal capacities along with that of the organization

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Desktop Support Engineer**

Elitser Technologies LLC PROJECT- EMIRATES NBD BANK on Windows Migration Sept 1, 2019 - Present

- Working for windows Migration Project in UAE as Desktop Support Engineer at Emirates NBD Bank.
- Performing Migration from Windows 7 to 10, Taking Backup and Restore in Windows Easy Transfer.
- Supporting End users for installing printers, scanners, Wacom Tablet Disk cleanups and hardware driver upgrades.
- Worked in Active Directory users and Computers for user and PC movement also to apply Policy for users.
- Troubleshooting DNS host entries, DHCP reservations
- Modifying & maintaining Share Folder NTFS permissions
- Planning, Implementing, Administration of Users, Computers, Groups, OU strategies, Create and Manage computer accounts, Mail Box, Manage user profiles
- Creating, Configuring, Managing and troubleshooting Group Policy objects
- Configuration and maintenance of Wi-Fi (D-Link)
- Network printers and scanners (Canon 3300 & Kyocera task Alfa 3010i) installation and troubleshooting.
- Remote support for all business applications through internet and LAN (SCCM remote)
- Having good knowledge about Symantac antivirus client installation and troubleshooting
- Installed, Configured & Managed Domain Controller (Windows Server 2008, 2012R2) Active Directory, Additional Domain Controller.
- Planned and implemented Active Directory administration (user creation, group management, group policy).
- Delivered services on all current platforms: Windows Server 2008, Server 2012R2 and Windows 10.
- Lead the acquisition, installation, and maintenance of the organization's LAN hardware and software, along with the development, repair, and upgrade of PCs, laptops, tablets, handheld devices, office equipment.

# Network engineer Feb, 2018 – April, 2019

Computer mart, Kannur, India

- Configured and installed routers, switches and wireless controllers.
- Managed switches, routers, firewalls and server equipment.
- Diagnosed network problems involving a combination of Hardware, Software, communication issues.
- Performing design and management of inventory records of all the IT equipment's including Servers and Client machines.
- Installation, Monitoring, Trouble shooting of CCTV Cameras & Configuring of DVR and NVR machines.

- Lead the acquisition, installation, and maintenance of the organization's LAN hardware and software, along with the development, repair, and upgrade of PCs, laptops, tablets, handheld devices, office equipment.
- Monitored and checked networks, workstations, operating systems, and software applications to ensure their proper functioning, as well as hardware and software were patched and updated.
- Performed troubleshooting of software, hardware & network failures, identified root causes & resolved it in a timely & accurate manner.

# E-Pub Developer/System Support

June, 2015 - Dec, 2017

Transcend Creative Service Pvt Ltd, Bangalore, India

- Worked on interactive E-pub samples and live production based on the latest web standards including HTML 5. Worked in XML, DTD, Schema and CSS.
- Experience in designing Cascading Style Sheets for various Electronic Publications based on HTML.
- Performed troubleshooting of software, hardware & network failures, identified root causes & resolved it in a timely & accurate manner.
- Responded to the employee complaints and provide technical assistance in troubleshooting errors, System
  restoring and malfunctioning.
- Install, maintain and provide user support for software applications.
- Install and maintain data communication hardware and software and support users.

#### **Projects**

1. E-Pub Development and XML

**Client: Peter Lang** 

Worked on E-pub and XML live production with the editorial companies based in Bern, Berlin, Brussels, Oxford and New York. Updated existing CSS to meet the client requirements.

2. Static Website

Client: Ivar

A static website contains web pages with fixed content. Each page is coded in HTML and displays the same information to every visitor. Used JavaScript, bootstrap, JQuery as plug-in.

#### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

Master of Computer Applications

NCM, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

• Bachelor of Computer Applications

Morazha Co-op Arts and Science College, Kannur, Kerala

# **PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

CCNA Certified [CISCO id: CSCO13461858]

MCSA Certified [MCid: 17347634 Certification No: H135-3104]

NAVISION

WEB DEVELOPMENT

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **OPERATING ENVIRONMENTS**

- Client Comfortable in Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 10 and Linux (Ubuntu).
- Server Windows Server 2008 to Windows Server 2016 and Exchange Server.

#### **HARDWARE**

- Installation and configuration of Operating Systems (Windows and Linux).
- Assembling of computers, Troubleshooting and Rectifying the Systems and Network Problems.
- Installing and configuring the peripherals, drivers, software and application to customer standards.
- Familiar with configuration of printers, scanners, and networking devices.
- Excellent troubleshooting skills in complex **software** and **hardware** problems.
- Provide data security and data recovery.

- Knowledge in VMware Client and basic knowledge in Server Infrastructure.
- Configure and troubleshooting systems remotely using SCCM Remote.

#### **NETWORKING**

- Configuration and maintenance of networking in small, medium and large office environment.
- Static Routing, Routing protocols RIP, EIGRP, OSPF and Routed protocol TCP/IPIPv4, IPv6.
- Imple6ent Network Security, NAT, PATandAccess Control List.
- VLAN, INTER VLANRouting, ACLand Trunking.
- Routers: Cisco 1800, 2620, 2621Switches: Catalyst 2950, 3550, 3560.
- Strong knowledge in OUTLOOK and AWS Cloud Services.

#### **SERVER - MICROSOFT**

- Deploying and Maintaining Active Directory Service, Group Policy in Windows 2008 and 2016 Servers.
- Configure and maintain DHCP Server, DNS Serverin Windows 2008 and 2016 Server.
- Configure and maintain policies for objects in Active Directory.
- Configuring and troubleshooting of Web server (IIS) and Exchange Server.
- Configuring and maintenance of Microsoft Outlook, Admin Center.
- Installing configuring administrating software applications.

#### **WEB DESIGNING**

- Keeping abreast of relevant new techniques in design software, media & photography.
- Excellent Skills in SEO, W3C Validation, Code validation, Java scripts etc.
- Good knowledge and Experience in Web Hosting, Domain Registration and Domain Transfer.
- Skilled in database Management using SQL.
- Software Visual Studio, Dream Viewer, Notepad++.

#### **OFFICE TOOLS**

- Excellent in MS Office Package.
- Using a variety of software packages, such as Microsoft Word, Outlook, PowerPoint, Excel, Access, etc. to produce correspondence and documents and maintain presentations, records, spreadsheets and databases.
- Photocopying and printing various documents, sometimes on behalf of other colleagues.
- Software -Microsoft Office2003/2007/2010/2013, ORACLE Open Office org.

## LANGUAGES KNOWN

Read &Write: English, Hindi, Malayalam

Speak: English, Hindi (Basic), Tamil (Basic) & Malayalam (Native)

## **PERSONAL PROFIL**

Age and Date of Birth : 28yrs.08February 19

Nationality : Indian

Visa status : Company Visa Passport no : N2761534

#### **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief. I can serve according to the organization's expectations and assure on as independent workmanship in concern if a favourable opportunity is offered.

Place: Yours Sincerely
Date: Jayakrishnan T V